<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>OPRE</title><link href="http://nacnudus.github.io/opre/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://nacnudus.github.io/opre/feeds/miscellaneous.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://nacnudus.github.io/opre/</id><updated>2015-07-14T00:00:00+12:00</updated><entry><title>The tortoise and the hare move house</title><link href="http://nacnudus.github.io/opre/the-tortoise-and-the-hare-move-house" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-14T00:00:00+12:00</updated><author><name>Duncan Garmonsway</name></author><id>tag:nacnudus.github.io,2015-07-14:opre/the-tortoise-and-the-hare-move-house</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Someone in my flat emigrated last week, leaving behind 13 boxes for the shipping
company.  When the van man arrived and saw the 40 steps leading up to our flat,
he nearly passed out.  I offered to&amp;nbsp;help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The van man man and I are different&amp;nbsp;builds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="./images/451px-strong-vs-weak-clip-art-1502408.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the strong van man carried two boxes at a time down the steps, I carred
only one, and then ran back up for another.  The final score was seven to him,
and six to me.  How did I keep up?  Without being unkind, the van man&amp;#8217;s strength
came with bulk.  Taking his own body into account, he carried a lot more than I
did, half of the journeys &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt; the&amp;nbsp;steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be interesting to find out how well animal bodies optimise themselves
for physical exertion.  If a professional house mover is on a healthy diet, does
their strength and bulk tend towards an optimum solution of the strength/bulk
trade-off?  Anyone&amp;nbsp;know?&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Underwear sizes of flood victims</title><link href="http://nacnudus.github.io/opre/underwear-sizes-of-flood-victims" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-10T00:00:00+12:00</updated><author><name>Duncan Garmonsway</name></author><id>tag:nacnudus.github.io,2015-07-10:opre/underwear-sizes-of-flood-victims</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Wellington Cathedral of St Paul (in New Zealand) has this newsletter&amp;nbsp;item:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whanganui&amp;nbsp;Floods&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to the recent floods that have devastated
parts of the Whanganui district, [someone] from the Parish of
Eastern Whanganui is collecting &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEW&lt;/span&gt; unides/knickers.  That&amp;#8217;s right - undies!
These will be distributed to families in need in the region.  All shapes,
sizes and colours will be gratefully&amp;nbsp;accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What size of underwear ought donors to donate?  A few options come to&amp;nbsp;mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their own&amp;nbsp;size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The size of someone they know in&amp;nbsp;Wanganui.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A random sample from a shop where they live (around&amp;nbsp;Wellington).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A random sample of a shop in&amp;nbsp;Wanganui.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing your own size is an easy stragegy to implement, but it only works under
certain assumption.  Are the donors of underwear similar in weight and balance
of sexes to the receivers?  Does anyone have access to demographics of New
Zealand Anglican&amp;nbsp;parishes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing the size of someone one knows in Wanganui has a couple of advantages
over the first strategy.  First, parisoners of Wellington Cathedral may well
know parishoners of Eastern Whanganui.  Supposing the receivers of undies are
from all of Whanganui, not just the parishioners, it is still likely that people
know people.  This is a small&amp;nbsp;country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, donors may also know children in Wanganui, whereas they probably
aren&amp;#8217;t children themselves.  This is an important point for the third strategy:
sampling from a shop in Wellington.  &lt;a href="http://www.bendonlingerie.co.nz"&gt;Bendon Lingerie&lt;/a&gt;
surely doesn&amp;#8217;t stock children&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final strategy might be best, since a clothes shop in Wanganui probably
understands the local market as well as anyone.  But I&amp;#8217;d be concerned for people
in the tails of the undie-size distribution.  The people in extreme need are the
people at the extremes.  Since too-small undies can usually stretch, a good
strategy would tends to under- rather than over-stimate the size of the
population.  Overestimates are useless &amp;#8212; the dungers fall&amp;nbsp;down.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>